Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (VADP); Records apap304
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Communication, 1981-2007; 4; 1.2 cubic ft.
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Contacts, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 68)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Initiative, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 69)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Bassette, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 70)
  - Miller Center, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 71)
  - Moratorium in Virginia, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 72)
  - Muhammad Vigil, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 73)
  - People of Faith Mailing, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 74)
  - Roanoke College Guest Lecture, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 75)
  - Senate Bill 333, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 76)
  - Summerlin Argument, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 77)
  - Soros Justice Fellowship, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 78)
  - Thank You for Attending Virginia Core, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 79)
  - U+L Law Guest Lecture, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 80)
  - Unspoken Prayers, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 81)
  - UVA Law Guest Lecture, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 82)
  - VADP Arrington Country Fair Booth, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 83)
  - Virginia Capital Clearing House, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 84)
  - Virginia core Juvenile Death Penalty Session, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 85)
  - Virginia People of Faith, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 86)
  - Weekend of Faith, 2004 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 87)
  - 21 Day Rule, 2004; Undated (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 88)
  - University of Richmond Guest Lecture, 2004; Undated (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 89)
  - Bruce Williams, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 90)
  - Emails, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 91)
  - Looth Execution, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 92)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Bassette, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 93)
  - Sample Emails for the Courts Justice Committee, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 94)
  - Santa Clara University Article, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 95)
  - National Death Penalty Archive Dedication Invitation, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 96)
  - VADP Action Alerts and Media Alerts, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 97)
  - VADP Leadership Change, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 98)
  - Virginia House Bill 1800 Capital Murder by Gangs, 2005 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 99)
  - Virginia Innocence Commission, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 100)
  - Amnesty International, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 101)
  - Emails, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 102)
  - Equal Justice and Fair Play, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 103)
  - National Conviction of Jail and Prison Ministry, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 104)
  - Tennessee Coalition to Abolish State Killing, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 105)
  - VADP Action Alerts and Media Alerts, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 106)
  - Virginia Pardon and Parole Board, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 107)
  - Shannon Valentine, VA General Assembly, 2006 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 108)
  - Emails, 2007 (Box 1 (4-Communication), Folder 109)
  - Georgia State Board of Parole and Pardons, 2007 (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 1)
  - Mid- Atlantic Innocence Project, 2007 (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 2)
  - NCADP, 2007 (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 3)
  - VADP Action Alerts and Media Alerts, 2007 (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 4)
  - Virginia General Assembly, 2007 (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 5)
  - Virginia Plus, 2007 (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 6)
  - Form Letter for Attorney General Terry, Undated (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Joe Giarratano, Undated (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 8)
  - Response - Prison Pen Pal Question, Undated (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 9)
  - The Exonerated Flyer, Undated (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 10)
  - VADP Crime Commission Letter, Undated (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 11)
  - VADP Mailings, Undated (Box 2 (4-Communication), Folder 12)
- Activities, 1992-2007; 5; 1.6 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials related to projects and programs hosted and or attended by Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty.
  - 21 Day Rule Project, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 1)
  - Looth Execution, 2002; 2005; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 2)
  - 2002 NCADP Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 3)
  - 2003 NCADP Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 4)
  - 2004 NCADP Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 5)
  - 2002 National Weekend of Faith, Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 6)
  - 2003 National Weekend of Faith, Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 7)
  - 2004 National Weekend of Faith, Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 8)
  - 2005 National Weekend of Faith (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 9)
  - 2006 National Weekend of Faith, Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 10)
  - 2003 Starving for Justice (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 11)
  - 2003 VADP Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 12)
  - 2005 VADP Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 13)
  - 2004 VADP Death Penalty Awareness Day (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 14)
  - 2004 VADP Fast and Vigil (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 15)
  - 2006 VADP Fast and Vigil (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 16)
  - 2005 Virginia Catholic Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 17)
  - 2007 Virginia Catholic Conference (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 18)
  - 2007 Virginia Cure Packet (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 19)
  - ACLU Student DD Conference Packet, 2003; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 20)
  - Activism Conference, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 21)
  - A Day for All People of Faith, 2007; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 22)
  - Alliance to End Juvenile Death Penalty, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 23)
  - Amnesty International DP Packet - French, 2002 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 24)
  - Amnesty International Mid Atlantic Conference, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 25)
  - Breaking the Cycle of Violence, Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 26)
  - Broken Justice, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 27)
  - Catholic Advocacy, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 28)
  - Centerville High School, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 29)
  - Christopher Scott Vigil, 2007 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 30)
  - Commonwealth Litigation Packet, 2004-2006; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 31)
  - Death Penalty Awareness Day, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 32)
  - Death Penalty Awareness Day, 2006; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 33)
  - Death Penalty in the US, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 34)
  - Death Penalty Issue Packet, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 35)
  - Death Penalty Press Conference Materials, 2003-2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 36)
  - Declaration of Life, 2006 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 37)
  - Execution Vigil, 2007 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 38)
  - Faith, Values and Capital Punishment In Virginia, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 39)
  - For Whom the Bell Tolls Project, 1999 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 40)
  - Freedom Information Advisory Council, 2001; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 41)
  - Friends Committee and Commonwealth Legislation, 2007 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 42)
  - Investigating Capital Cases Conference, 2003 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 43)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Packet, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 44)
  - Juvenile DP Awareness Day Packet, 2005 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 45)
  - Listening Project - [RESTRICTED], 1993-1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 46)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Listening Project for Chris B. - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Video-tape 36)
  - Montreal Death Penalty Conference, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 47)
  - Moratorium, 2000 (Box 1 (5-Activities), Folder 48)
  - Moratorium Now Packet, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 1)
  - Muhammad and Malvo Trial Vigils, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 2)
  - People United, 2005 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 3)
  - Religious Organization Against The Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 4)
  - Respect Life Packet, 2006 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 5)
  - Robin Lovitt Vigil, 2005 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 6)
  - Summit to Strategize for Abolition, 1997 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 7)
  - The Moratorium Campaign, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 8)
  - VADP Fast and Vigil, 2005 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 9)
  - VADP Legislative Survey, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 10)
  - VADP Martin Luther King Jr., 2007; Undated (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 11)
  - VADP Write-A-Thon, 2006 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 12)
  - Virginia Core, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 13)
  - Virginia Friends Advocacy Day, 2005; Undated (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 14)
  - Virginia General Assembly Catholic Advocacy Day, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 15)
  - Virginia General Assembly Day for People of Faith, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 16)
  - Virginia General Assembly Death Penalty Awareness Day, 2006 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 17)
  - Virginia General Assembly Interfaith Advocacy Day, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 18)
  - Virginia General Assembly Jewish Advocacy Day, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Activities), Folder 19)
  - Vigil for Walter Cole and James Hudson, 2004 (Box 3 (5-Activities), Folder 1)
  - Virginia House Representatives Survey, 2004 (Box 3 (5-Activities), Folder 2)
  - Virginia Journey of Hope, 2006; Undated (Box 3 (5-Activities), Folder 3)
  - Virginia Methodists Death Penalty Workshop, 2001; Undated (Box 3 (5-Activities), Folder 4)
  - Virginia Moratorium Resolution Campaign, Undated (Box 3 (5-Activities), Folder 5)
- Petitions, 1993-2004; 6; 1.2 cubic ft.
  This series consists of petitions, including the "Moratorium 2000" petition and the "Stop Look and Listen" petition.
  - 21 Day Rule Petitions, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 1)
  - Abolition of the Death Penalty Petition, 1993 (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 2)
  - Justice for Giarratano Petition, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 3)
  - Moratorium 2000 Petitions, 2000-2001 (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 4)
  - Moratorium 2000 Petitions (1 of 2), 2000-2002 (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 5)
  - Moratorium 2000 Petitions (2 of 2), 2000-2002 (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 6)
  - Moratorium 2000 Petitions (1 of 3), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 7)
  - Moratorium 2000 Petitions (2 of 3), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 8)
  - Moratorium 2000 Petitions (3 of 3), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 9)
  - Moratorium 2002 Petition, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 10)
  - Moratorium in the USA Petition, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 11)
  - Petition Cards, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 12)
  - Petitions from Religious Groups, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 13)
  - Resolution for a Moratorium on Executions in Virginia Petition, Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 14)
  - Stop Look and Listen Petition (1 of 4), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 15)
  - Stop Look and Listen Petition (2 of 4), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 16)
  - Stop Look and Listen Petition (3 of 4), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 17)
  - Stop Look and Listen Petition (4 of 4), Undated (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 18)
  - VADP Petition Database (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 19)
  - VADP Petition Database (2 of 2), 2004 (Box 1 (6-Petitions), Folder 20)
  - Virginia Moratorium Petition (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2 (6-Petitions), Folder 1)
  - Virginia Moratorium Petition (2 of 2), Undated (Box 2 (6-Petitions), Folder 2)
- Subject Files, 1937-2007; 7; 6.05 cubic ft.
  This series contains a number of materials that Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty researched or used to further the organization's efforts to end capital punishment in Virginia. Topics consist of the juvenile death penalty, lethal injection, and national and international stances on the death penalty. Formats include clippings, journal articles, VHS tapes, banners, and a customized license plate.
  - 21 Day Rule Articles, 1999-2000; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - 21 Day Rule, 2000-2001; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - 21 Day Task Force, 2000; 2003; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - 60 Minutes, 1995-1996 (Video-tape 1)
  - 85 Recommendations, Undated; 2005 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - 2nd Circuit Court of Appeals, 2002 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - 2nd World Congress Against the DP, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - 4th Circuit Court of Appeals, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - 11th Circuit Court of Appeals, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - 1000th Execution, 2005 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - 2004 Election, 2003-2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - 2005 Bill Outcomes (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - ABC News, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - ABC the Practice, Undated (Video-tape 3)
  - ACLU Capital Punishment, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - After Exoneration, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - AI Invitation, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - AI Report on Lethal Injections, 1950-1952; 1985; 1987; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Alan Gell, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - The American Agenda, 1957 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Amnesty International Fourteen Days in May, Undated (Video-tape 4)
  - Amnesty International Human Rights for All, 2003 (Cd 1)
  - Amnesty International Rights for All, Undated (Video-tape 5)
  - Amnesty International USA Reports "Israel and the Occupied Territories", Undated (Video-tape 6)
  - Amnesty International the Campaign Against the Death Penalty, 1986; 1989 (Video-tape 7)
  - Amnesty International "Lighting the Flame of Conscience", Undated (Video-tape 8)
  - Amnesty International "The Next Step", Undated (Video-tape 9)
  - An Execution in Doubt, Undated (Video-tape 10)
  - Ann Mengi, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Ashcroft, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Attorney General Killgore, 2004-2005 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Attorney Standards, 1992; 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Arizona Death Row, 2002 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Australia Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Bajito Onda Foundation English and Spanish News Clips and Testimonials, 2002 (Video-tape 11)
  - Bassette Hearing Form, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Beheading, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Biological Evidence After 21 Days, 2002; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Bill Pelke Speaking Tour, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Bishop's Statement on Death Penalty, 2007 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Black Colleges NCADP Tour, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Blackmun, 1994 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Book Order, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Brain Finger Printing and the DP, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Brain Research, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Burden of Innocence, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Bush, 2000; 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - California Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Catholic Church and Death Penalty, 1990; 2004; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Catholic Diocese of Richmond Slide Show, Undated (Video-tape 12)
  - CBC Documentary on AVP Badoc Workshop-Workworth Institution Ontario, Canada, Undated (Video-tape 13)
  - Child Molesters, 2006 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - China Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Children Behind Bars, 1999 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Christians and The Death Penalty, 1980; 1994-1995; 1997-1998 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Christians Perspectives, 1979 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Christmas Card, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Civilization and the Death Penalty, 1983 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Choice is Yours, Roger Coleman. No More Choices, Undated (Video-tape 14)
  - Coleman DNA, 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Commuted DP Sentences, 1991; 1995; 2000; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Conference Evaluations, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Connecticut Death Penalties, 2005 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - "Convicts Who Plead Guilty Claim Innocence", 2002 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Conservatives and the DP, 2000; 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Cost of U.S. Prisons, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Cuba Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Danville Leads VA In Death Row Inmates Per Capita, 1998 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Dead Man Walking, 1996 (Video-tape 15)
  - Death is Different, 1993 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - The Death of Justice, 2005 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - The Death Penalty, 1987 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Death Penalty, 1992-1994; 1996-1997; 1999 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Death Penalty and Race, 1994; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Death Penalty and Religion, 1999; 2004 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Death Penalty Articles (1 of 3), 1985; 1988-2005; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Death Penalty Articles (2 of 3), 1985; 1988-2005; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Death Penalty Articles (3 of 3), 1985; 1988-2005; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Death Penalty Awareness Day, 1990; 2000-2001; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Death Penalty Banner (with Spray Paint), Undated (Oversized 1)
  - Death Penalty Banners, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Death Penalty Cast, 1983; 1987-1989; 1993; 1997-1998 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Death Penalty Debated, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Death Penalty Doubts By Bush, 2005 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Death Penalty in the South, 2003 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Death Penalty in the USA, 1990-2007; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Death Penalty Lawyers, 1986; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Death Penalty Location Link in VA, 2001 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Death Penalty Newspaper Articles (1 of 2), 1986-1990; 1992-1995; 1997-2005; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Death Penalty Newspaper Articles (2 of 2), 1986-1990; 1992-1995; 1997-2005; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Death Penalty Stickers, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Death Row Exonerees, 2002-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Death Row Pen Pals, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Death Row Prisoners as Productive Members of Society, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Delaware Death Penalty, 2003; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Delma Banks, 2003-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Dewey Cornell, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Discriminatory Practices in the Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - DNA Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - DNA Evidence, 2002-2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - DNA on Trial, 2000 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - DNA Testing, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Doctors and Execution, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Doctors and Lethal Injections, 1980; 1982; 1985-1986; 1988-1989 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - DP and Deterrence, 1981-1982; 1985; 1988-2000; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - DP and Execution Volunteers, 2003-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - DP and Mental Health, 1990; 2001-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - DP and Mental Illness, 2002-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - DP and Mental Retardation, 1997; 2001-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - DP and Politics, 2000; 1990 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - DP Articles, 2005-2007; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - DP Forum Fahey Ethal, Undated (Video-tape 16)
  - DP Hellen Pajama Lady, 1994 (Video-tape 17)
  - "The DP is Permissible", 1986 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - DPIC and Innocence, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - DPIC Handouts, 2006-2007 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - DPIC Weekly Updates, 2006 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - DPIC Weekly Updates, 2007 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Drawings by Death Row Inmate, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Equal Justice and Fair Play, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Eric Nance, 2005; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Ethics Articles, 2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - "The Executioners", 2000 (Video-tape 18)
  - "The Execution of Child Offenders", 2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - The Execution of the Innocent, 1999 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Execution Witness Bill, 1994 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - The Exonerated, 2001 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Eye Witnesses, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Eye Witnesses and Exonerations, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Facing the Death Penalty, 1998 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Facts for Action, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - False Confessions, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Fear of Crime and the Death Penalty Study, 1957 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Felon's Rights, 2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Fill the Field, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Final Wishes, 2007 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Florida Death Row, 2002-2004; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Flyers, 2003-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Friends Committee on Common Wealth Legislature, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - "From Hatred to Mercy", 2006 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - "From Victim to Victimization", 1986 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Future Dangerousness, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Herbert Bassette, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - General Assembly, 2001; 2003-2004; 2006 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Georgetown Law, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - The Genius of Death Row, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Georgia Moratorium, 2006; 2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Gonzales, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Gospel of Life, 2006 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Governor Kaine, 2007 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Gun Violence, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Habeas Corpus, 2000 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Handouts, 2004-2007; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Illinois Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Imagine the End of the Death Penalty, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - "Indecent and Illegal the Death Penalty Against Child, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Indiana Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 65)